Guide to the Provost Charles Peake Administrative Records, 1967-1971 UA.3.1.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- R.O.T.C., 1968 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  Newspaper clippings about R.O.T.C. controversy with annotations by Dr. Peake. Dr. Peake's reply to faculty members regarding article in Pitt News, December 6, 1968.
- R.O.T.C., 1967-1968 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  Correspondence about controversy over eliminating credit for R.O.T.C. courses and R.O.T.C. status in university.
- R.O.T.C. Controversy, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  Memos, reports, faculty and student meetings on allowing R.O.T.C. to remain at University and if so, allowing credit for it, 1968; student/faculty protests over R.O.T.C.
- Regional Campuses, 1969-1970 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  Letters to advisory boards; minutes of presidents' meetings, 1966-1967; operating and other financial statements; weekly admissions reports, 1970.
- Regional Campuses, 1966-1968 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  Material for annual report, 1966-1967; schedule for graduate instruction; memos on finances; memo on natural sciences program; liaison with School of Engineering; Freshman survey Fall, 1966; policy statements, 1968; enrollment projections, 1968; policy on credits beyond 60 hours.
- Regional Campuses, 1967-1968 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  Memos concerning admissions; ten-year projections; operations and financial reports; memos on relationship of Oakland campus and Regional campuses; memos on dormitory construction; compensation for Regional campus presidents; proposals for growth.
- Religious Studies, 1966-1969 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  Proposed cooperative graduate program in study of Religion with Pittsburgh Theological Seminary and related correspondence, 1966; publication; "The Study of Religion on the Campuses of Today;" NY Times article on lack of religious courses at Pitt, March 16, 1969; proposal for department of religion, 1969; letters on candidates for faculty positions in future department of religious studies, 1959 and 1962.
- Reorganization of University, 1967-1970 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  Memo from Chancellor establishing Provost office, College of Arts and Sciences, and Director of Communications, 1967; Proposed reorganization of graduate study, 1970.
- Science Center, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  Research and consulting group organized by faculty of Pittsburgh universities and hospitals to serve industry; Dr. Brinkloe; memos, brochures, article about Center.
- Science Education Improvement Institute, Proposal by Edward Gerjuoy, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 9)
- Senate Council - Correspondence, 1964-1970 (Box 34, Folder 1)
- Seoul University/Pitt Cooperative Program, 1967-1969 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  Memos on visiting professors from Seoul, Korea; bibliography on English language material on Korea and its education, 1968; correspondence and proposal to Gulf Oil Co. to support cooperative program conducted by Center for International Studies, 1969.
- Slavic Languages and Literature Department, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  Memos on administration of Department and conflict correspondence departments program and faculty, 1970.
- Slavic Languages and Literature Department (Box 34, Folder 4)
- Social Psychology (Box 34, Folder 5)
- Social Psychology (Box 34, Folder 6)
- Social Psychology, Committee on Graduate Study of (Box 34, Folder 7)
- Social Injustice Programs, 1968-1969 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  Proposal for program in Black history and culture; proposals for programs in various academic areas to eradicate social injustice; cost analysis of programs; related correspondence.
- Social Work, Graduate School, 1967-1969 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  Memos and correspondence on operation of school; proposals for overseas programs and scholarships for minorities; program of field work in McKees Rocks office of Pittsburgh, 1968.
- Social Work, Graduate School, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  Progress report – International Dimensions of School, 1970; survey of students on graduation ceremony, 1970; memos on grants: Hillman, Kaufman, UJF; memos on tenure.
- Social Work, Graduate School - Workshop Summary Reports, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 11)
- Social Work, Graduate School, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  Malcolm-Martin-Marcus Scholars program policy statement; correspondence about Black students; proposal for new careers development; proposal for 3rd year program of black and related subjects; proposal for recruiting black male social workers; position statement on charges of racism; admission policy; proposal for Graduate School of Social Work formulated by "nucleus" committee.
- Social Work, Graduate School, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  Search Committee for new dean, 1970; committee membership list; concerns of black students on selection of dean; position papers by faculty for director of the School; message in alumni newsletter from retiring dean.
- Social Work, Graduate School, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  Correspondence about consultants on directors for School of Social Work; faculty-student proposals for Social Action; statistics on dean's salaries from Council on Social Work Education.
- Social Work, Graduate School - Proposed Undergraduate Program, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 4)
- Social Work, Graduate School - Proposed Undergraduate Program, 1967-1970 (Box 35, Folder 5)
- Social Science Information Center, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  Prospectus for Center, programs proposed, related memos, 1967.
- Social Sciences Building, 1967-1969 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  Proposed building (Mervis Hall) for Division of Social Sciences, January 1967 and revised June 1967; description of Institute for Social Research and Social Science Information Center; memo on location in Forbes Quadrangle, 1969.
- Sociology Department, 1969-1970 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  Position as head of department declined, 1959; memos about establishing social problem institute, 1969; administrative correspondence on Research Bureau for Retail Training analysis of dress shopping, 1935; acceptance of rayon by women customers analysis, 1934 (Both analyses based on lazerfield techniques).
- Sociology Department, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  Report on development of department 1966/1967; memos on administration of department; basic design for study of world student movement, 1968; memos on relationships with other universities; position paper on student activism signed by faculty; letter from Dr. Avery on temporary assignment at International Christian University, Tokyo, on student riots there; funding in Pittsburgh White Attitudes study; proposal to Mellon Foundation on study of the Arts, 1969.
- Sociology Department (Box 35, Folder 10)
- Sociology Department (Box 35, Folder 11)
- Space Research Coordination Center, 1967-1969 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  Minutes of faculty council meetings, 1967-1969; correspondence on grants from NASA, Sarah Mellon Scaife Foundation; memos on SRCC administration.
- Speech and Theatre Arts, 1967-1970 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  Proposal for laboratory theatre and mission of speech department, 1961; memos on problems facing university theatre, 1965; planning memos for theatre arts, 1967; description of department programs and plays; news release for theatre productions; report on theatre technology; proposed major in dance to be associated with Department Theatre Arts, 1970; application to Pennsylvania Department of Education for program in speech and hearing, 1970.
- Speech and Theatre Arts (Box 36, Folder 3)
- State Relatedness - Funding Crisis (Box 36, Folder 4)
- Student Affairs, 1966-1970 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  Policy on dormitory priorities; memo on university scholars recognition; memos on housing, student employment, Pitt News; news release of various appointments in Student Affairs.
- Student Affairs - Student Programs, 1966-1970 (Box 36, Folder 6)
- Student Affairs - Admissions, 1969-1970 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  Weekly admission reports for fall 1970 prepared March-June 1970; controversy and clarification of duties of Black recruitment and admissions office, 1969-1970.
- Student Unrest, 1968-1969 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  Primarily articles about unrest at other universities; several opinions by Pitt faculty; HEW instructions on student assistance for student activists; ACLU statement on civil disobedience.
- Student Participation in University, 1969-1970 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  Memos on student participation study committee; notice of student demonstration; report on campus disturbance at Brooklyn College, 1967; letters from students; statement from American Civil Liberties Union; Fall 1970 course evaluation; Report of student conduct, Brown University.
- Student Participation in University, 1968-1970 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  Correspondence and memos concerning establishment of student cabinets in each school; proposal for an all-university council; messages from Chancellor on student participation and racial justice; paper from CMU on student's rights and responsibilities, 1970.
- Student Registration, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  Proposal for handling students taking a few courses, from other universities, for high school students, 1970; memos on student aid, married student housing, transfer students; graduate degrees by department, 1962-1963.
- Studio Arts Department, 1968-1970 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  Policy statement on studio programs and art education, 1968; design for new studio arts department; proposal for new undergraduate program in the college; proposal for master's degree in Studio Arts, 1970; correspondence about hiring Henry Koerner as artist in residence.
- "T" General Correspondence (Box 37, Folder 3)
  Suggested task forces on high quality faculty, undergraduate education, communication services, regional campuses, 1967; report on teaching effectiveness, 1965; report on task force on state master plan for higher education and related correspondence, 1969; Theta Chi Fraternity honors Dr. George Crouch, 1969; TV courses correspondence.
- Teacher Corps Program, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  Proposal for Teacher Corps in Pittsburgh, 1967-1970; news release on Teacher Corps Conference, 1968; programs at various city schools; Office of Education, HEW recommendation of expanding teacher corps; University Senate Resolution on Corps; Office of Education grant to Pitt.
- Tenure Policy, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 5)
- Tenure Survey, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  Survey of major universities on their tenure policy; copy of questionnaire; list of universities contacted and memo giving results, 1969.
- Titusville Campus, 1968-1970 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  Correspondence on operations of campus, advisory board, engineering curriculum, and dormitory construction; 10 year plan and policy statement; financial statements for 1968-1970.
- Titusville Campus, 1966-1968 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  Correspondence on administration of Titusville campus; brochures and musical programs.
- Transportation and Traffic Safety - Proposed Center, 1967-1969 (Box 37, Folder 9)
- Tuition, 1966-1969 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  Decrease in tuition rates due to state-relatedness; memo on tuition and fees.
- Undergraduate Academic Council - Student Representatives, 1968-1969 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  Meeting minutes, 1968-1969; policy recommendations; memos on various student cabinets; proposed all-university council, rejected.
- Undergraduate Teaching Committee (Box 37, Folder 12)
- University-Community Educational Program, 1969-1970 (Box 37, Folder 13)
- University-Community Educational Program - Coordinating Committee, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  Proposal to set a committee to coordinate programs for disadvantaged; list of committee members.
- University-Community Educational Program, 1968-1969 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  Correspondence about administration of program; proposal for research in Pittsburgh during current racial crisis, 1968; budgets for U-CEP.
- University-Community Educational Program, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  Reports from various schools on proposed programs for disadvantaged; interim report to chancellor, 1968.
- University-Community Educational Program, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  Description and history of Pitt programs for disadvantaged.
- University-Community Education Program, 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  Reports on various programs and proposals for helping the culturally disadvantaged; minutes of study group for proposed programs; programs in Graduate School of Public and International Affairs; proposed budgets.
- Urban and Environmental Systems, Center for Study of, 1968-1969 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  Drafts of proposal to set up Center to plan research programs for urban and environmental studies, 1968-1969; correspondence between Provost and School of Engineering faculty on establishing Center; Proposals on setting up evaluative research programs; paper on environmental systems engineering program in School of Engineering, 1968-1969; responses to proposal from deans and department heads, 1968-1969.
- Urban Programs, 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  Correspondence on University Council on Urban Programs; minutes of council; symposium paper on urban government by Donald Stone, 1968; memos on task forces for community use of physical education building and African American relations; proposal for university urban interface; proposal for racial crisis research; papers on urban studies in Departments of Economics, History, Political Science, Sociology, Anthropology; OEO grant application.
- Urban Programs, 1961-1968 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  Working paper for Tumble Run meeting on Industrial Civilization, 1961; Report to Chancellor on urban programs, 1967; proposed center for aid to low income groups by Meyer Schwartz of Social Work, 1968; proposals for university help to poor communities; paper: "The University and Urban Environment"; program to develop black organizers and planners; proposal for urban advocacy center and lab.
- Urban Programs, 1967-1969 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  Correspondence on the University's role in urban development in Pittsburgh; draft – University of Pittsburgh Urban Development and Services Program, July 19, 1977, and first edition, August 1967; Model City Agency general plan for education, November 1968; H.E.W. paper, 1969; Congressional paper "Directory of Urban Research Study Centers."
- Weidlein Professorship (Box 39, Folder 1)
  Dr. W.L. Garrison appointed first Weidlein Professor for Environmental Engineering; correspondence relating to appointment and his ideas for the department.
- Western European Studies, 1968-1970 (Box 39, Folder 2)
- Peake Personal Correspondence - Congratulatory Letters on Provost Appointment and Retirement (Box 39, Folder 3)